Finding Aid for Michigan Office of the Auditor General records, 1840-1937
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Office of the Auditor General records 1840-1937
Michigan. Office of the Auditor General.
1 linear foot
898 Ca 2
Miscellaneous records of the Michigan Office of the Auditor General.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The provenance of these records is unclear. Donor no. ( 7522 )
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The mission statement of the Office of the Auditor General (OAG) is to improve the accountability of public funds and to improve the operations of State government for the benefit of the citizens of the State of Michigan. The OAG best accomplishes its mission by committing to total quality; by adhering to the professional standards of the auditing profession; and by promoting an atmosphere of mutual trust, honesty, and integrity among OAG staff and the people they serve.
In its history, the duties of the Office of the Auditor General of Michigan have varied. In addition to auditing accounts of the State Treasurer, the Auditor General was also concerned with the sale of lands delinquent for taxes.
The record group consists of miscellaneous materials received as part of the accessioning of the papers of Governor William Milliken. Most of the records date in the mid-1930s, although there are some items dating as early as 1840. The record book includes a letterpress book (1842-1850) as well as balance sheets and financial work sheets, 1934-1937; statement of operations, 1934-1936, of the Michigan War Loan Sinking Fund; and appraisal book of Dewey and Hazelton asset lands.
Subjects:
Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950
- Miscellaneous records
  - Letterpress book, 1842-1850, of correspondence of auditor general; and scattered accounts, 1842-1844 (Box 1)
  - Receipt book, 1840-1841, of Bank of Michigan (Box 1)
  - Charge Book, 1894-1895, to Michigan counties (Box 1)
  - Appraisal of Dewey and Hazelton asset lands (Box 1)
  - Report of the Examination of the Books and Records of Macomb County, October 1930-September 1931 (Box 1)
  - Statement of Operations, Michigan War Loan Sinking Fund, 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Balance Sheets, Highway Construction Fund, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Balance Sheets, Michigan General Fund, 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - Board of Equalization Work Sheets, 1937 (Box 1)